Carlos Eduardo Pontual de Lemos Castro

Rua Silva Jatahy, 500 – Ap 500 – Meireles Fortaleza, CE – CEP: 60.165-070

Objective

Software Engineer

Resume

Technical leader. BSc and MSc on Computer Science, with focus on software engineering. Carlos Eduardo is an enthusiast of technology with a passion for new challenges. He has vast experience on development of mobile applications, on numerous plataforms. Currently he develops apps and games for Android devices.

Education

MSc on Computer Science

jan 2008 – jun 2010

Informatics Center (CIn) / Federal University of Pernambuco (UFPE) Dissertation title: Design Rules for Increasing Modularity with CaesarJ

BSc on Computer Science

jan 2004 - dec 2007

Federal University of Ceará (UFC)

Experience

Group of Computer Networks, Software Engineering and Systems (GREat)
System Analyst dec 2010 – present

- Technical leader of two Android apps projects
- Development of apps and games for Android devices
- Development of automatic tests for Android platform
- Analysis and development of Country Adaptations for mobile phone carriers Feature Phone (C/C++) / Android

doistempos.com

Software Consultant

feb 2007 - jan 2008

- Design and development of doistempos.com Mobile e-commerce application (JME)
- Design and development of mobile applications with .NET Compact Framwork (C#, Web Services, SQL Server)

Group of Computer Networks, Software Engineering and Systems (GREat) Scientific Initiation Scholarship (PIBIC/CNPq) jan 2005 – jul 2007

- Development of mobile app UbiPEP Ubiquitous Medical Prontuary (JME)
- Maintenance and implementations of new features on CGR GREat Asset Manaement System (PHP, MySQL)
- Development of a tool to collect network routers data GET-RNA (Java)

Other

Xlung

Projects

Systems Analyst and Software Consultant

may 2012 – present

 Analysis, project design and development of xlung.net web portal (Ruby On Rails / Passenger)

Courses

Asp.NET MVC 2.0, 40h - OpenGL ES, 16h - Windows Phone, 30h

Skills

Programming Languages: Android, Java, Ruby, C#, C, C++, Python, PHP Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Qt, .NET MVC, .NET Compact Framework

Databases: MySQL, SQLite e SQL Server

Development on operational systems Linux, Windows and Mac (OSX)

Software versioning systems SVN, ClearCase and Git Agile software development methods (Scrum and XP)

Additional Info Brazilian, 27 years old, single, no children

Idiomas: Portuguese (Native), English (Fluent), French (basic)

Oracle Certified Java Programmer 6

Lattes CV: http://lattes.cnpq.br/9333882757346321

LinkedIn profile: http://www.linkedin.com/pub/carlos-eduardo-pontual/4/

17a/291